http://www.synergist.co.uk/privacy-policy

Synergist is forMD & OwnersFD & FinanceProject Managers & Client ServicesResource & Scheduling ManagersFeaturesTime & MoneyOnline timesheetsJob / project costingBilling softwareQuoting / estimatingPurchasingAccounts IntegrationPlanning & TrackingSchedulingKanban BoardsCapacity planning softwareProject planningJob / project trackingPipeline ManagementCommunicating & SharingDocument managementCRM softwareiPhone / Android AppOnline Approval & DAMEmail integrationRemote WorkingReporting & ManagementDashboardsAlertsKey reportsScheduled reportsDrag and Drop reportingSee how the information flows togetherUser storiesAgenciesProject-basedPricingInfo HubGuidesReportsCommon Problems SolvedMigrating to SynergistOur BlogFAQsGDPRContact usClient areaCloud log inPrivacy PolicyPrivacy PolicyIntroductionWe respect privacy and your rights to control your personal data. Our approach is to be clear about the data we collect and to explain why and how we process it.The prime purpose of collecting your data is to improve the product and service we deliver. Whether you're a prospective customer evaluating Synergist or a current user, our aim is for you to receive the full benefits of Synergist with the best service we can deliver.This privacy statement outlines the information we (Synergist Express Ltd) collect and how we use this information.Our postal address is: Synergist Express Ltd, Clarence Mill, Clarence Road, Bollington, SK10 5JZOur registered address is: 1 City Road East, Manchester, M15 4PN Registered in England no. 4697775What information do we collect?When Learning about Synergist, information you provide to us:It's likely that in learning about Synergist you will visit a website we own, and may voluntarily provide us with personal information via an enquiry form which you can use to; request a demo, request information on Synergist Express Ltd’s products and services or to make an enquiry about other things such as jobs or press opportunities. From these forms we collect the following information: visitor's name, contact phone number, email address and company.Our site also has a marketing sign-up form which visitors can use to opt-in to receive our marketing communications. From this form, we collect the following information: visitor's name, contact phone number, email address, job title and company.We will never sell the information you provide to any third party and only share the information submitted via the above forms with our trusted sales / implementation partner The Agency Works. If you have requested more information about Synergist or a one-to-one demo, The Agency Works will be responsible for replying and/or delivering your demo.Information we collect automatically:We automatically collect information by cookies and similar technologies when you use, access or interact with us via our websites. This may include information about the type of device you use to access our websites, the operating system and version, your IP address, your general geographic location, as indicated by your IP address, your browser type, the webpages you view on our websites, whether you interact with content available on our websites and how.When using Synergist, information you provide to us:Once you become a Synergist user you may be asked for information so that we can process your purchase / subscription request and provide support and maintenance services to you. We collect the following information: Contact name, contact phone number, job title, postal address & email address.Information we collect automatically:We automatically collect information by cookies and similar technologies when you use, access or interact with us via our product or websites. This may include information about the type of device you use , the operating system and version, your IP address, your general geographic location, as indicated by your IP address, your browser type, the webpages you view on our websites, whether you interact with content available on our websites and how. We also collect functional and usage data from Synergist to fulfil the contract we have with you and to improve the product and service we provide. Functional data would include volume of attached files, numbers of licences / subscriptions installed on your Synergist / Synergist Cloud instance. Usage data includes volume of data created segregated by type.How do we use this information?We may use the information you have supplied via our forms to get in touch with you if necessary, respond to your demo request or respond to your enquiry. We use the data we collect to deliver and personalise our communications with you. For example, we may contact you by email or via the Synergist interface to inform you about new features, security or software updates, update you on a support issue or invite you to take part in a survey. This processing is necessary to serve our legitimate interest.If you have opted-in, you will also receive our marketing communications. We will keep a record of your relationship with us and record the contact we have had with you.Information collected about website visitor behaviour is used to help us analyse web traffic and improve the content of our website for our visitors. You can find more about this in the 'what is a cookie' section of this document.Functional data such as volume of attached files on your Synergist Cloud instance is used for billing purposes and number of licences installed to ensure you have access for the correct number of users at any time. Both Functional and Usage data is used to ensure your cloud instance is suitably resourced to deliver adequate performance, diagnose problems and to asses the level of use of different features to influence future product developments.Third Party VendorsWe use a carefully considered selection of third-party vendors and their systems to carry out services like website management, support ticket management and email communications. We only share your personal data as necessary. Your personal information will be shared with these third parties but only for the purpose of performing services on behalf of Synergist Express Ltd and in accordance with this policy. It is our legitimate interest to process your personal data for these purposes.Examples of this include:Mailchimp to send email communications and also track whether you open the emails we send you and which links you are clicking on to improve our future communications.Zendesk to manage support tickets to ensure we provide a structured, timely and responsive support service via both email and phone.How secure is the information that we collect?We follow industry standard security measures to prevent the loss, misuse and alteration of the information that is under our control.Does Synergist Express Ltd pass on information gathered to any third party?Synergist Express Ltd does not sell or disclose information obtained about website visitors or customers to anyone outside of Synergist Express Ltd and The Agency Works, unless specifically authorized by you, law requires it or disclosure is necessary to protect the safety of customers, employees or property, or as detailed in the 'Third Party Vendors' section above.How do we protect the information that we have collected?Synergist Express Ltd  shall endeavour to take all reasonable steps to protect any data you give to us via the website including the use of encryption technology, but cannot guarantee the security of any data you disclose online over the Internet. You will not hold Synergist Express Ltd or The Agency Works responsible for any breach of security unless Synergist Express Ltd or The Agency Works have been negligent or in wilful default.Website Visitor InformationDuring the course of any visit to synergist.co.uk the pages you see, along with a short text file called a 'cookie' are downloaded to your computer. Information supplied by cookies can help provide a better online user experience and assist us to analyse visitor profiles.What is a cookie?A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a website's computer and stored on your computer's hard drive. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser's preferences allow it, but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a web site to access the cookies it has already sent to you, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.For further information on cookies please visit http://www.aboutcookies.org.Use and storage of your personal informationWhen you supply any personal information to us we have legal obligations towards you in the way we use the data. We must collect the information fairly, that is, we must explain how we will use it and tell you if we want to pass the information on to anyone else.Synergist Express Ltd ensures that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with GDPR 2018.RetentionWe will retain your personal information for as long as we deem it necessary to enable you to use our websites and product, to provide services to you, to comply with applicable laws (including those regarding document retention), resolve disputes with any parties and otherwise as necessary to allow us to conduct our business. All personal information we retain will be subject to this Privacy Statement and our internal retention guidelines. If you have a question about a specific retention period for certain types of personal information we process about you, please contact us: Synergist Express Ltd Express Ltd. Clarence Mill, Bollington, Cheshire SK10 5JZWho to contact?If you have submitted personally identifiable information through Synergist Express Ltd websites and would like that information deleted from our records or would like to update your information, please contact us: Synergist Express Ltd Express Ltd. Clarence Mill, Bollington, Cheshire SK10 5JZWe will use reasonable efforts to delete this information from our existing files.Access to your personal informationYou have the right to request a copy of the personal information that Synergist Express Ltd holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. Please address requests to Synergist Express Ltd, Clarence Mill, Bollington, Cheshire, SK10 5JZUsers 16 and underIf you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to us. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.LinksWe are not responsible for the content or privacy policies of any sites we may link to.
